Łukasz Cieśluk

Personal details

Residence: London, UK

GitHub: https://github.com/garciapl blog: https://garciapl.github.io

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/lukaszciesluk

Summary

Professional Software Engineer with over seven years of extensive experience in the financial, telcom, advertising and commerce industries. Highly self-motivated individual contributor and team player focused on a clean code approach combined with high quality. An advocate of automation in projects and enthusiast of open source.

Experience

Nov 202I - now

Software Developer, Bloomberg LP London, UK

Bloomberg AIM (Asset and Investment Manager) - Compliance

Stack: Python, Behave, Pytest, Docker

Dec 2017 - Oct 2021

Senior Software Developer, Bloomberg Data Management Services Dublin, Ireland

Market Index Data for Enterprise Data Management called Bloomberg Data License Plus (DL+)

Stack: Java, Python, Spring (Boot, Data, MVC, Cloud Netflix), Maven, Flyway, Oracle, Guava, JUnit, Mockito, AssertJ, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Git, Ansible, Swagger, Elasticsearch, JavaScript, ExtJS, Microservices

Apr 2017 - Nov 2017

Senior Software Developer, Datalex Limited Dublin, Ireland

- I. Develop application for storing and managing flights and other additional services
- 2. Bring code style within clean code approach and new practices in terms of development and testing
- 3. Compose performance scripts in JMeter
- 4. Perform code reviews along with mentoring other developers

Stack: Java, Gradle, RESTEasy, MongoDB, Morphia, JUnit, Mockito, Hamcrest, JMeter

Aug 2015 - Mar 2017

Software Developer, Brandtone Dublin, Ireland

- I. Develop primary campaign management system that engages consumers through different channels like IVR, SMS and USSD. First developer of Konnect engagement platform which empowers marketers to maximize ROI and build deep relationships with consumers Involved in developing Trader solution which helps traders improve selling their products
- 2. Cooperation with QA's, DevOps, DBA's, Architects and other Developers to build software which meets business requirements and KPIs
- 3. Participate in Agile Sprint planning, backlog refinement and retrospectives
- 4. Experience of working in environment which requires excellent troubleshooting, analytical skills, ability to be self-organised, strong interpersonal, communication skills and experience with a number of stack components and tools

Stack: Java, Spring (MVC, Data, Security, Batch, Integration), Maven, Oracle, Guava, Git, JUnit, Mockito, Grunt, Bower, Flyway, Docker, Ansible, ActiveMQ, AWS, Angular, React, Redux

Aug 2014 - Jun 2015

Senior Java Developer, Digital Virgo Warsaw, Poland

- I. Develop mobile Value Added Services e.g. massive SMS sending service. Design dedicated standalone client for lottery system. Support developers involved in mobiParking project. Implement SMS Payment Gateways responsible for charging clients for content and services
- 2. Collaboration with business analysts around fulfilling client requirements
- 3. Partnership with developers responsible for the frontend

Stack: Java, Spring (MVC, Data), Maven, Oracle, Git, Swing, Python

Nov 2013 - Jul 2014

Software Developer, AgreeYa Mobility Poland Warsaw, Poland

- I. Develop supply system dedicated to the medical industry in accordance with customer requirements
- 2. Direct collaboration with the client in order to select technologies and solutions applied
- 3. Composition of technical and user documentation of produced software

Stack: Java, Python, Django, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL

Jul 2012 - Oct 2013

Software Developer, Bank Gospodarstwa Krajowego Warsaw, Poland

- I. Leading role in incorporate new extensions of system responsible for monitoring bank infrastructure e.g. execution of money transfers, network stability, databases availability and other banking systems
- Support supervisor during the design and implementation of new data models and graphs commissioned by Bank management and other departments
- 3. Overall system administration and maintenance

Stack: Java, Perl, Oracle, MySQL, Cisco, Nagios

The intern was founded in 17 edition of the competition "Grasz o Staż" organized by PwC

Jul 2011 - Sep 2011

Software Developer (intern), Telekomunikacja Polska S.A. Warsaw, Poland

Implement tool improving the efficiency of administrator work around collecting and analysing Call Detail Records (CDR) used for billing customers for paid services

Stack: Java, Perl, PostgreSQL

The intern was founded in 16 edition of the competition "Grasz o Staż" organized by PwC

Jul 2010 - Sep 2010

Software Developer (intern), Orange Poland Warsaw, Poland

Support administrators in the current surveillance and response to the failure of IT systems responsible for the proper operation of the GSM/UMTS mobile networks. Develop tools to improve and enhance operational efficiency

Stack: Perl, Bash

The intern was founded in 15 edition of the competition "Grasz o Staż" organized by PwC

Education

Feb 2011 - Oct 2012

Politechnika Bialostocka (Bialystok, Poland)

Faculty: Computer Studies

Specialization: Smart Internet Technologies

Degree: MSc

Thesis: Analysis tools used to implement the concept of Telco 2.0

The master thesis was carried out in collaboration with <u>Orange Poland</u> under initiative Orange Labs Telco 2.0 University

As the part of the thesis was developed application called Eventoo which aims to monitor the correlation between the area defined by event organizer for instance as a festival and the location of participants based on the operator localization interface to provide statistics and tools to collaborate with them

Framework - Spring (Core, Data, Web)

Database - MongoDB UI - JSP, jQuery

APIs - Orange Location and SMS API, Facebook API

Oct 2011 - Feb 2012

Politechnika Lodzka (Lodz, Poland)

Faculty: Technical Physics, Computer Science and Applied Mathematics Specialization: Systems in management and electronic commerce

Degree: MSc

The semester has been completed as part of a student exchange program called MOSTECH dedicated to students of technical universities

Oct 2007 - Feb 2011

Politechnika Bialostocka (Bialystok, Poland)

Faculty: Computer Studies

Specialization: Designing Application Systems

Degree: BSc

Thesis: Secure communication using SMS

Platform - Java ME

Cryptographic algorithms - DES, AES

Scholarships

2011 - 2012 University President Scholarship at Politechnika Bialostocka

2010 - 2011 Scholarship at Politechnika Bialostocka

Certifications

Feb 2018 Bloomberg Market Concepts (BMC)

May 2016 ScrumMaster by Scrum Alliance (License no. 000527091)

Nov 2015 | Java SE 7 Programmer I (IZO-803)

Languages

Polish: native

English: upper-intermediate

Additional

Skills

Languages | Java, Python

Frameworks | Spring (Boot, Data, MVC, Cache, Batch, Integration)

Databases Oracle (PL/SQL), MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis

NoSQL | MongoDB

Web Servlets, JSP, JSON, HTML, REST

XML | XPath, XQuery, XSLT, JAXB

Application server | Apache Tomcat

Persistence Hibernate, JPA, JDBC, PL/SQL Message Broker RabbitMQ, ActiveMQ, Apache Kafka

Testing | JUnit, Mockito, Hamcrest, DbUnit, WireMock, AssertJ

ELK Elasticsearch, Kibana

Version Control | Git, Subversion

Libraries Guava, Apache Commons, JodaTime, Lombok

IDE IntelliJ, Eclipse

Operating Systems | Linux, Windows

Build automation | Maven | Database Migration | Flyway | Cloud | AWS*

DevOps Docker, Ansible SDLC Scrum (Agile)

Collaboration JIRA, BitBucket, Confluence CI/CD Jenkins, Nexus, SonarQube

Principles | SOLID

^{* -} in progress